Guide to the Oregon State University Military Photographs Collection 1875-1975
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
- Cold War Years, 1946-1975; Series V
  - Cadet Officers, OSU ROTC, group photo, circa 1962; P002:570; 4X5 photographic print (Box 2)
    Posed group photo of Army ROTC Officers of the 1962-63 year. These men appear in other photos in this series. Identification of cadets is on reverse: "1st Row, L to Rt:, 1st Lt. Michael Kasner S-2, 1st Lt. Donald Pearson S-4, Col. Delbert Ball C.O., Capt. Rodney Stubbs S-3, 1st. Lt. Donald Page S-1, 2nd Row:, W/O (Warrant Officer) Duane Mahoney, W/O Rodney Commons, W/O Leigh Worthing, W/O John Watkinson, W/O Gene Sites, W/O Stephen Titus.
  - U. of Alaska ROTC "Pledge's Revenge", circa 1960; P002:573; 5X5.5 photographic print (Box 2)
    University of Alaska Pershing Rifles ROTC Company A-11 R. Painted door with Pledge flag colors. Caption on reverse explains: Pledges' Revenge: Pledges indignant over the loss of their pledge flag that was taken by the miners get revenge by painting a flag on the entrance to the University mine. P.I.O. photo."
  - U. of Alaska Co. A-11, pledge flag on water tower, circa 1960; P002:575; 5X7 photographic print (Box 2)
    University of Alaska, ROTC Pershing Rifles unit A-11. Caption on reverse: Pledge flag hung proudly on the campus water tower before it was stolen by the miners. University of Alaska Company A-11th Regiment, P.I.O. Photo."
  - Trophy display Drill Competition 1961, P002:742; 3.5X3.5 photographic print (Box 2)
    Display of trophies from the Drill Team Competition 1961-62 which the unit won first place. This photograph appears to show the 3 place trophies, probably before presentation.
  - Trophy display Drill Competition 1961 #2, P002:743; 3.5X3.5 photographic print (Box 2)
    Display of trophies from the Drill Team Competition 1961-62 which the unit won first place. This photograph appears to show the 3 place trophies, probably before presentation. Duplicate of P002:742
  - ROTC Mock Legislature with speaker, circa 1960; P002:745; 4X5 photographic print (Box 2)
    ROTC meeting in legislative building (unidentified). ROTC Banners at both sides of head table. Speaker at lectern at center is unidentified.
  - ROTC cadet officers in dress uniforms, circa 1960; P002:746; 1.0 print; 5X7 photographic print (Box 2)
    Four Army ROTC officers posed photograph. Men are wearing dress uniforms of the circa 1960 time period. 3 officers are infantry and 1 Engineers based on collar badges. Seated officer name tag "Looney", two of the three standing officers, "West" and "Hirte".
  - ROTC Cadet officers by Pershing Rifles HQ, circa 1960; P002:747; 5X7 photographic print (Box 2)
    Four Army ROTC officers in posed photograph outside door of the Pershing Rifles Headquarters, circa 1960. Same officers as described in P002:746; officer name tag "Looney", "West" and "Hirte". with one unidentified.
  - Six ROTC Officers U of O, unit G-11, circa 1960; P002:748; 4X5 photographic print (Box 2)
    Unidentified group of six Army ROTC officers, posed photograph in dress uniforms. Markings on reverse list the photo as G-11, which is the Pershing Rifles regiment for University of Oregon, Eugene. Photo appears to be of 1960 vintage.
  - Two unidentified ROTC officers shaking hands 1963, P002:749; 4X6 photographic print (Box 2)
    Two ROTC officers shaking hands, Barometer Photo 1/23/63. Stamped on back with date and marked "wed baro w/sotry" Uniforms indicate USAF Cadets based on badge on service cap on right.
  - Army Colonel shaking hands with 2 men with Piper aircraft, circa 1960; P002:750; 5X7 photographic print (Box 2)
    US Army Colonel shaking hands with two men by a Piper civil aircraft. Marked on reverse with Barometer photo stamp, date of 4/7 with no year listed. Other markings state "ROTC" and "c.1960". Dating may be consistent based on uniform and type of Piper Colt, private airplane.
  - Cadet officers with Drill Competition trophies, March 1962; P002:751; 3.5X3.5 photographic print (Box 2)
    Dated March 1962, the Officers are with the drill team trophies won at the competition just prior to the Sand Point NAS meet. Unidentified cadets in this photo, others in Sand Point NAS sub series have names on reverse.
  - Cadet officers with Drill Competition trophies 1962, March 1962; P002:752; 3.5X3.5 photographic print (Box 2)
  - Cadets on patrol, climbing hill, March 1964, P002:753; 3.5X3.5 photographic print (Box 2)
    View of cadets with field packs and rifles climbing road a hill. Location is unidentified, but appears to be local based on trees/terrain. Men are wearing fatigues with field packs and carrying M-1 Garand rifles. Photo is dated March 1964.
  - Unidentified Army ROTC Cadet, dress uniform, circa 1960; P002:754; 5X7 photographic print (Box 2)
    Unidentified Army ROTC Cadet officer in dress uniform. Posed photograph outdoors. Uniform and badges are circa 1960, prior to issue of name badges to cadets.
  - Testing of USAF rocket motor, circa 1960; P002:780; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    Stock military photo, stamped on reverse: "Photo by United Technology Corp. (Photographic Dept.) Sunnyvale, Calif." No date listed. Photograph of a USAF missile rocket motor being tested in bunker on the side of a wooded hill. Photo was probably used for an article in the Oregon Stater, or for USAF ROTC training.
  - Award presentation USAF ROTC Cadets, circa 1960; P002:781; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    Five Air Force ROTC Cadets receiving award of cadet badges from USAF officer. Unidentified subjects in photo, USAF officer Colonel rand with pilots wings. Photo probably used for OSU publication.
  - Army ROTC Cadet receiving award, circa 1960; P002:782; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    US Army officer shaking hand of ROTC Cadet at unidentified ceremony. Cadet is in dress uniform with white laces in combat boots. Officer shaking hand is of Major or Lt. Colonel rank. Possibly a Pershing Rifles Drill Team awards ceremony as the cadet has ceremonial bloused trousers and white "ladder" lacing in his combat boots.
  - Army ROTC cadets viewing guard dog kennels, circa 1960; P002:783; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    Army ROTC Cadets viewing german shepard guard dog in kennel at unidentified base, circa 1960. Cadets are probably visiting Ft. Lewis for training. Overcoats and service caps are of the post 1955 vintage. This photograph was probably used for OSU publication.
  - Air Force ROTC Cadets being briefed by USAF crew member, circa 1960; P002:784; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    USAF Crew Chief of military transport aircraft (Possibly C-130 Hercules) briefing OSU Cadets about cargo bay details. Air Force ROTC Cadets are wearing standard rain coats with rain covers on service caps. The USAF Crew chief is wearing flight suit with squadron badge on chest (unreadable in photo).
  - Cadets with heavy artillery display, Ft. Lewis, circa 1960; P002:785; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    Two cadets (OSU ROTC) viewing the bore of a 155mm "Long Tom" Heavy Artillery piece on display at Ft. Lewis Washington. Photo is marked in pencil on reverse with "Oregon State", probably indicating the cadets are OSU ROTC. Stock publicity photograph, probably intended for OSU publication.
  - Dwight Eisenhower and 2 unidentified men, circa 1955; P002:786; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    Dwight D. Eisenhower with 2 unidentified men in suits, holding book. The M.V. Seven Seas book is being looked at by the men, unknown connection to OSU. The MV Seven Seas was a cruise ship of the Europe-Canada line in the 1950s.
  - USMC officer swearing in recruits, circa 1961; P002:787; 6.5X9 photographic print (Box 2)
    US Marine Corps officer swearing in a group of recruits while second officer looks on. Photograph can be dated to 1960-1963 based on the presidential photo of John F. Kennedy on wall behind cadets. Unknown location and subjects, presumably OSU cadets, in civilian clothing.
  - Navy ROTC Cadets viewing scale model ship in testing facility, April 1964; P002:788; 5X7 photographic print (Box 2)
    Stock photo for Barometer publication 4/14/1964. US Navy ROTC cadets viewing scale model ship in testing tank at OSU Lab, 1964. Photograph is stamped on reverse: "Barometer Photo, date to run: 4/14/64" and "Photo by D. McKellar"
  - University of Alaska cadets with snow track display, circa 1962; P002:808; 5X7 photographic print (Box 2)
    University of Alaska Company A-11 of the 11th Regiment of Pershing Rifles. Caption of photo: "Cadets of Company A-11th Regiment of University of Alaska see the motor pool at Fort Wainwright in action. P.I.O. photo"
  - Stock US Navy Photo of Ensign dipping water in Antarctica, Jan 1963, January 1963; P002:565; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    Caption on reverse: Task Forse(sic) Forty Three, XAM-31768-1-63, 15 Jan. 1963, Ens. Harold S. Hemphill USN, Assistant Photographic Officer of Air Development Squadron Six gets a bottle of water out of a seal hole at McMurdo Sound, Antarctica. the bottle of water is for ceremonial use in the United States. Credit line to read "Official U.S.Navy photograph by Photographers Mate Second Class (PH2) Thomas J. Regina PH2 USN" The officer in the photograph is probably an OSU ROTC Graduate, and the photo was forwarded on for publication.
  - Freshman Platoon marching on campus 61-62, April 1962; P002:715; 3X4.5 photographic print (Box 2)
    ROTC Pershing Rifles freshman platoon marching on campus, 61-62 year. This photo is combined with the Sand Point Competition sub series, probably by the same photographer. Notes on reverse: "a freshman platoon of Ore. St. University E-11". Related photo to P002:442 which show this group in background behind drill team.
  - Freshman Drill Team, OSU Co. E-11, marching on campus, circa 1962; P002:442; 4X5 photographic print (Box 2)
    Photo of Pershing Rifles Co. E-11, Freshman drill team marching on campus in 1962. Caption on reverse states; "The freshman drill team with a freshman platoon in the background. E-11"
  - ROTC Cadet officers, duplicate of P002:747, circa 1960; P002:789; 5X7 photographic print (Box 2)
    Four Army ROTC officers in posed photograph outside door of the Pershing Rifles Headquarters. Same officers as described in P002:746; officer name tag "Looney", "West" and "Hirte". with one unidentified. Second copy of photograph.
  - ROTC Freshmen squads by McAlexander Field House, April 1962; P002:716; 3X4.5 photographic print (Box 2)
    ROTC Pershing Rifles freshman platoon marching on campus, 61-62 year. This photo is combined with the Sand Point Competition sub series, probably by the same photographer. Notes on reverse: "Freshmen, two squads at E-11"